[{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in meaning to the italicized words in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He cannot hide his <em><u>aversion<\/u>&nbsp;<\/em>for Kemi's unrepentant behaviour.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["abhorrence","sadness","ignominy","moodiness"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I am sure all those who mistook President Buhari's _________ demeanour for cowardice will soon know him for who he actually is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stealthy","Sloppy","Snaky","Succulent"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in mening to the italicized words in this sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The <em>investments<\/em> in stocks seemed to have gone down the drain with this meltdown in the banking sector<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Business","Capital","Surpluses","Dividends"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in meaning to the italicized words in this sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My efforts at making her see my point were&nbsp;<em><u>rebuffed<\/u><\/em>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embraced","Antagonized","Snubbed","Successful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in mening to the italicized words in this sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He is a&nbsp;<em>lout<\/em> and can't be relied upon at all.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Vagabond","Thug","Unserious","Liar"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in mening to the italicized words in this sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The undisputed boxer was quite a <em>mouthful&nbsp;<\/em>for his opponent.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Not a match","Undefeated","Evenly match","Boastful"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the best option nearest in mening to the italicized words in this sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Such stories are difficult to believe because they are&nbsp;<em>make-belief.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Lies","Vituperations","Genuine","Fantasy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gaps in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The new Inspector General of Police alleged that terrorists had________ the rank and the file of the force.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Proliferated","Conquered","Infiltrated","Insulated"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gaps in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He lay awake, his whole body______ sleep.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acting for","Looking for","Drumming for","Aching for"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gaps in the following sentences.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Please think______ everything and let me have your answer tomorrow<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Thoroughly","Through","Around","On"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/b><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I guess he is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">indifferent<\/span> to our plans to rid Nigeria of societal ills.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Interestd in","Opposed to","Bothered","Not interested in"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposites in meaning to the underlined word.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The increase in transportation cost&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">imperilled<\/span> my sister's plan to travel this month.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Propelled","Restricted","Disturbed","Hoodwinked"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The criminal's answers to the questions during interrogation were&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">evasive<\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Harsh","Outspoken","Clever","Direct"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The high-profile witness has been discredited having been accused of being_______ with the truth in his testimony.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Biological","Geographical","Circumventing","Economical"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gaps in the following sentences.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The jailed businessman has left his family in _________ due to the confiscation of his property by the government.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bliss","Quandary","Opulence","Eldorado"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While the host community was condemned roundly for their hostility, the visiting contingent was applauded for their ___.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Friendliness","Hospitality","Dexterity","Methodology"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It is hard to quantify that ________ the abducted Chibok girls would have gone through since they were taken away by the dreaded Boko Haram insurgent.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rape","Trauma","isolation","Insecurity"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option to complete the gap in the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The Federal Government has expressed the fear that the violent activities of the insurgents may ________ if powerful foreign assistance is not received soon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Extrapolate","Proliferate","Metamorphose","Escalate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank spaces in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The driver was reckless, the road was slippery due to the early morning downpour, and _________ there was a crash that claimed two lives.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Frantically","Subsequently","Consequently","Unequivocally"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Did you know we were very fortunate to run _______ for the newly elected president of the country when he was campaigning for the office?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Errant","Run errands","An errand","Around"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I am sure that if you probe further, the accused person will reveal where the ________ money is kept.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pilfered","Missed","Lost","Robbed"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I was waving frantically but you, drove _________ me.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Past","Pass","Passed","Passing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the italicized words in the sentences below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You need to go and study the <em><u>etymology<\/u><\/em> of the underlined words in the returned essay, the lecturer told the student.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["meaning","technicality","originality","origin"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the italicized words in the sentences below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The&nbsp;<em><u>erratic<\/u><\/em> power supply these days has caused a lot of damage to household items that use electricity.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["lackadaisical","regular","uneven","high-voltage"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the correct option to fill the blank spaces in the sentence below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He won the elections but many people were killed by his thugs, and thus many said he was a _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Philistine victory","Pyrrhic victory","Crocodile victory","Pseudo victory"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The aspirant for the highest office in the coming elections has started distributing live cows to each electorate in his ward, but some rejected it because they considered it a _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["An Eldorado gift","Grievous gift","Greece gift","Greek gift"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The workers expressed&nbsp; their heartfelt thanks _______ the management for the notable improvement to their conditions of service.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Toward","With","Towards","To"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The man told him point-blank that his argument was bereft _________ sound reasoning<\/strong><\/p>","options":["With","Of","In","Off"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Nobody could say precisely when the landlord became a&nbsp;<em><u>recluse<\/u><\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["loner","drunkard","nincompoop","cantankerous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If&nbsp; I had I had known his delicate state of mind, I would not have&nbsp;<em><u>broached<\/u>&nbsp;<\/em>the matter<\/strong><\/p>","options":["told them","divulged","brought up","cancelled"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Don't talk like that; you know the Professor will not entertain such&nbsp;<em><u>vituperative<\/u><\/em> remarks.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["irresponsible","insulting","angry","illiterate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My daughter would become________ if I paid no attention to her behaviour.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rhascally","Rhapsodically","Rascally","Rascality"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When the soldier saw that resistance was________ they stopped fighting.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inadvertent","Futile","Inappropriate","Insurmountable"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The last time the man saw his ex-wife, she ___________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Was thinking of a proposal of starting a new business.","Was intending to start a new business.","Intended to start a new business","Was going to start a new business."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Two days before the execution, the robber was taken to the place where he would be________ with doleful eyes,&nbsp; he looked at the post where his execution ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hunged\/was to be taken place","Hanging\/shall take place","Hung\/would take place","Hanged\/was to take place"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>'Don't_______', said the leader, I want a decision now'.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prevaricate","Predicate","Precipitate","Bepejorative"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word or phrases in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He has been advised to beware of political&nbsp;<em><u>jobbers<\/u><\/em> if he hopes to succeed.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Neophytes","Masquerades","Stockbrokers","Masterminds"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word or phrases in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What a <em><u>tangled<\/u><\/em> web we weave, when we try to deceive!<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Complicated","Crooked","Simple","Loose"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the word or phrases in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>She devoted too much time to the <em><u>peripheral<\/u><\/em> aspects.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Superficial","Minor","Main","Real"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the letter which contains the correct phonetic symbol in the underlined sound below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>W<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">o<\/span>men<\/strong><\/p>","options":["\/l\/","\/e\/","\/ou\/","\/u\/"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which contains the correct sound as given in the sound below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>\/v\/<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Off","Fan","Of","Four"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The car owner does not think about the __ of his vehicle and other payments involved in owning it.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Transportation","Depreciation","Calculation","Appreciation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We shall offer a good job to a ____ to registe guests in the Central Hotel.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Waiter","Watchman","Cashier","Receptionist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There is not___ sense in what that politician has just said.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Many","Plenty","Lot of","Much"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill in the&nbsp; gaps in the following sentences with appropriate preposition<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Lawrence did not win the contract___ the long run<\/strong><\/p>","options":["At","In","On","To"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill in the gaps in the follwing sentences with appropriate preposition<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Memun was careful not to fall ______Ameen's tricks<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Into","For","In","With"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill in the gaps in the following sentences with appropriate preposition<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The commander had placed his troop __ alert.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In","On","At","Over"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>What is the name of the subordinate clause in this sentence?<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I don't understand what<em>&nbsp;exactly you were saying.&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adverbial clause","Nominal clause","Adjectival clause","Interrogative clause"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Are you going to Lagos _________ your car ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["With","In","Through","By"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">Another name for relative clause is __________<\/strong><br><\/p>","options":["Adverbial clause","Infinitive clause","Adjectival clause","Relational clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the&nbsp; option the word or phrase that is nearest in meaning in meaning to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My efforts at making her see my point was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">rebuffed<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["embraced","antagonized","snubbed","successful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose from the&nbsp; option the word or phrase that is nearest in meaning in meaning to the word underlined<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He is a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">lout<\/span> and can't be relied upon at all.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["oaf","thug","unserious","liar"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the correct option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The speech was delivered with great&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">trepidation<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["fear","dexterity","power","creativity"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He cannot hide his&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">aversion<\/span> for Kemi's unrepentant behaviour.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["abhorrence","sadness","ignominy","moodiness"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My sister is known by everybody to be&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">scurrilous<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["pleasant","vituperative","active","inactive"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The criminal's answers to the question during interrogation were <u>evasive<\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Harsh","Outspoken","Clever","Direct"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I guess he is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">indifferent<\/span> to our plans to rid Nigeria of societal ills.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Interested in","Opposed to","Bothered","Not interested"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The girl is very&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">somber<\/span> in her style of dressing.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Solemn","Pleasant","Provocative","Exposing"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Select from the options the correct meaning of the idiom underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The manager behaved as if he&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">had bats in the belfry<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["He was pleasant","He had strange ideas","He was speechless","He was angry"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Select from the options the correct meaning of the idiom underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I learnt Agnes was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">off colour<\/span> this morning. She was not in class.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Busy somewhere else","Not able to wake up early enough","Not in her right mind","Not in good health"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the appropriate verb that best completes the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Although she suffered a lot of hardship she still _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gloated","Glowed","Flowed","Splashed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the appropriate verb that best completes the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Our plane______ down at Aminu Kano International Airport at exactly 12 midnight.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Landed","Descended","Got","Touched"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the appropriate verb that best completes the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The disease was_______ very rapidly in the community.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Widening","Catching people","Spreading","Raging"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the letter which contains the correct phonetic symbol in the underlined sounds below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Pl<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">um<\/span>b<\/strong><\/p>","options":["\/\u028cm\/","\/b\/","\/ph\/","\/p\/"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the letter which contains the correct phonetic symbol in the underlined sounds below.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>W<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">o<\/span>men<\/strong><\/p>","options":["\/I\/","\/e\/","\/ou\/","\/u\/"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the words that are closer in meaning to the words in initial positions.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Futile<\/strong><\/p>","options":["productive","fruitless","valuable","useful"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the words that are closer in meaning to the words in initial positions.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Halt<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Wait","Fault","Stop","Stay"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the words that are closer in meaning to the words in initial positions.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><b>Virtuous<\/b><\/p>","options":["Seeing","Good","Upright","Religious"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the words that are closer in meaning to the words in initial positions.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Renowned<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Famous","Popular","Well read","Familiar"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the words that are closer in meaning to the words in initial positions.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Solitary<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Private","Sultry","Alone","Lonely"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The car owner does not think about the ________ of his vehicle and other payments involved in owning it.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Transportation","Depreciation","Calculation","Appreciation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best complete the gap<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We shall offer a good job to a _______ to register guests in the Central Hotel.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Waiter","Watchman","Cashier","Receptionist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to word in italics.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Lola was&nbsp;<em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">agitated<\/span>&nbsp;<\/em>when the sad news of her mother's accident was broken to her.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Excited","Calm","Uncontrollable","Unreasonable"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The president took exception to the <em><u>ignoble<\/u><\/em> matter.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Honourable","Embarrassing","Dishonourable","Extraordinary"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The crowd in the hall is&nbsp;<em>intimidating&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["The crowd is frightening","The crowd is angry","The crowd is overwhelming","The crowd is riotous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The event of last Friday show that there is&nbsp;<em>no love lost&nbsp;<\/em>between the principal and the vice-principal.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["They like each other","They work independently","They cannot part company","They dislike each other"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Adawo is an&nbsp;<em>imp<\/em>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adawo behaves badly","Adawo behave decently","Adawo behaves differently","Adawo behave queerly"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There is no _____ sense in what that politician has just said.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Many","Plenty","Lot of","Much"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The candidate made_______ at the village square a day before the elections.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A sermon","An address","An eulogy","A speech"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best complete the gaps<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The city______ as a federal capital only________ the last twenty years.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Existed\/over","Has existed\/for","Was existing\/from","Is existing\/in"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best complete the gaps<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He is _______ Kaduna _______ an official assignment.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["At\/in","At\/for","In\/on","For\/in"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The members of the other team agree_____all the terms of contract.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["On","By","To","With"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the word which best fills the gap<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After Jerry had made the bed, he ________ on it.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Layed","Laid","Lied","Lay"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the word which best fills the gap<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The buildings damaged by the rainstorm______schools, hospitals and private houses.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Included","Include","Were included","Was including"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Fill the gap with the most appropriate option.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>_________ any problems, I shall travel to London tomorrow on a business trip.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In spite of","GivenWe use B","Barring","In case"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Fill the gap with the most appropriate option.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>'I can't stand people prying into my private life' Ladi said '_______' agreed Agbemu.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Me either","Me too","I also","Likewise myself"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><strong>Ch<\/strong><\/span><strong>eap:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Machine","Sheep","Chip","Chemist"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the letter underlined.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><strong>H<\/strong><\/span><strong>appy<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Our","Eyes","Honour","Behind"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word, as it is shown the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After finishing the 800 metres race, he fell asleep from&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">exhaustion<\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["weekness","fatigue","overwork","eagerness"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word, as it is shown the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The footballers went back to their camp <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sullenly<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cheekily","Quickly","Stubbornly","Resentfully"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word, as it is shown the sentence<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After Warri, on our way to Benin, we passed through a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dense<\/span> forest<\/strong><\/p>","options":["crowded","close","thick","heavy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word, as it is shown the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Last night, there was a very&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">fierce<\/span> rain storm<\/strong><\/p>","options":["raging","storming","angry","violent"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word, as it is shown the sentence.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The examiner said that the candidate's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">performance<\/span> in the examination was not good enough<\/strong><\/p>","options":["failure","achievement","e-marks","marks"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option that best complete the gap.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The editor was not happy that the Nigeria press was hemmed _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Up","Across","In","Over"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the options suggested, choose any one that best suits the context.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>More _____ to your elbow as you campaign for press freedom. <br><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Energy","Power","Effort","Grease"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the options suggested, choose any one that best suits the context.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>A child that shows mature characteristics at an early age may be described as _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Precocious","Ingenious","Premature","Preconceived"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>From the options suggested, choose anyone that best suits the context.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>That is a very terrible woman; every day she makes a lot of noise about one thing or the other. I'm not surprised, that's what her sisters _____ too.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are used to doing","Do","Always used to do","Are going"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Sir, I'm not lying about the matter, I know nothing of it. If I knew, ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I must tell you","I can tell you","I would tell you","I shall tell you"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><b><i>Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/i><\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Last night, there was a very&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">fierce<\/span> rain storm<\/strong><\/p>","options":["raging","storming","angry","violent"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the appropriate option to complete the following:<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The picture is\u00a0<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">ascribed<\/span> to Leonardo da Vinci. This means that _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Leonardo da vinci painted it","Leonardo da vinci might have painted it","Leonardo da vinci definitely painte it","Leonardo da vinci part of the painting"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><b><i>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/i><\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>As the examination progressed, it was observed that more candidate stared into space. This means many candidates<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Looked in to the sky","Looked straight for long but to nothing in particular","Looked through the window for would-be helpers","Tried to ensure that the spaces, between them were well maintained"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><b><i>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/i><\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You told me that Johnson is your trusted friend, why did you not&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">stand up for<\/span> him during his trial ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Defend","Ridicule","Pity","Disown"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>When you pronounce the word&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">university<\/span>, how many sounds could you perceive ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","4","10","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>They_____ arrived Lagos by now, all things being equal<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Had","Must","Might have","Would have"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the option that best completes the sentence:<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The pupils _______ so much noise that the teacher had to tell them to stand up and raise up their hands<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Had been making","Should have made","Were making","Had made"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I______ that he was insincere all along<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Could know","Must know","Should have known","May have known"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the correct option to fill the blank space in the sentence below.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If I had gone to Lokoja, I________ the opportunity of seeing the president<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Should not have had","Must not have had","Would have had","Should not have"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the preposition that best fills the gap in this sentence<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My sister does not have flair______ Mathematics<\/strong><\/p>","options":["At","In","With","For"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the preposition that best fills&nbsp; the gap in this sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When I got to her house, she was still&nbsp; _______ bed<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In","On","On the","In the"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the preposition that best fills the gap in this sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>During the demonstration, the anti-riot policemen were instructed to break _____ the student's defence line.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Off","Open","Through","Down"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the preposition that best fills&nbsp; the gap in this sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I was _______ hearing distance of the speaker<\/strong><\/p>","options":["At","In","On","Within"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Choose the one that best completes this sentence<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The electricity cable had to be ________ enough to be laid along the bend in the road.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Elastic","Taut","Compliment","Flexible"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the option that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We didn't have a lot of money, so I had to live quite ____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Niggardly","Frugally","Wastefully","Grudgingly"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the option that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I acted too impetuously, I do not know what ________ me.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Came along","Came over","Came at","Came on"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The hurricane raged for several days, leaving a trail of_____ across the land<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Destruction","Depoilation","Desperation","Demolition"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If a player breaks the rule during a match, one point will be______ to his opponent<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adjourned","Credited","Debited","Allied"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><b><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/b><\/p>\r\n<p><b>Mouse-traps are not always very effective, as some mice prove to be remarkably...<\/b><\/p>","options":["Inaccessible","Perpetual","Inconspicuous","Elusive"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>At the frontier, he hid watches in his pocket in order to ______ customs duty.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Evade","Incur","Repel","Deceive"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes&nbsp; the sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The driver was short of petrol, so he _______ down all the hills with the engine switched off.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Glided","Cut","Wheeled","Coasted"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Everyone in my family has a job. My mother is a teacher, my father is&nbsp; an engineer, and my granny<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Used to sell roast chicken","Is selling roast chicken","Has roast chicken","Sells roast chicken"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>One curious thing&nbsp; about my uncle is that he wishes _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["He is having eight wives","He had eight wives","He can have eight wives","He can be allowed to have eight wives"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I'm afraid, you know. My father has been sleeping since 4:00pm yesterday. It's about time ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["To wake up","He wakes","He woke up","He's awake"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Are you deaf ? I asked you _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["How old  you were","How old are you","How old is your age","What is your age"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What is a sentence ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is made up of words","It is made up of phrases and clauses","It is a group of words giving a complete sense","It can be simple or complex"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong><em>Choose the one that best completes the sentence<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What is a phrase ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is a group of words containing a finite verb","It is a group of words giving a complete sense","It is a group of words not containing a finite verb","It  usually begins with a preposition of a particle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of a finite verb is&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Going to school every day","Given his position as the principal","While going to school","While they were going to school"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is tense ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It has to do with present, past and future times","It is a correspondence between the form of the verb and  the concept of time","It is derived from the latin word 'transpire'","It is a controversial topic in linguistics"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is aspect ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It is a manner in which the verbal action is experienced or regarded","It reflects the attitude or mood of the speaker","It is made up of progressive and perfective forms","It is normally joined together with tense"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>What are minor sentences ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["They are complete sentences","They are incomplete statements","They are incomplete statements but normally function as sentences","They are used by writers for economical purposes"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In measuring one's linguistics competence in a particular language, itemize four sentences types that one need to master<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Simple, complex-multiple, difficult  and more difficult","Simple, complex, compound and compound-complex","Simple, more-simple, difficult, more difficult","Rational, more rational, logical and more logical"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"}]